# Usama Qureshi

## Unity Game Developer, AR/VR Designer & Developer

Karachi, Pakistan usamaqh@gmail.com +(92) 346-5348843

To serve in a progressive organization offering job satisfaction, a challenging yet enjoyable work environment and vast opportunity for career development that utilizes & extends my multi-skill knowledge, capability & work experience.

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

## Work Experience

## **Lead Interactive Application Developer**

Solution Founder Information Technologies Global - Karachi October 2021 to Present

• To design & develop multiple market level products such as real time AR coloring book, prototypes for Ludo Multiplayer game, AR weather checking using Midair AR, real time AR cosmetics wear.

#### AR/VR Designer & Developer

Digichowk Pvt. Ltd. - Karachi February 2019 to Present

- To design & develop market required, industrial based interactive AR, VR, multi-purpose, multi-player & multi-platform applications.
- Team lead.

#### Interactive Application Designer & Developer

Abbtakk News

June 2017 to November 2018

- To design & develop interactive AR, VR & general purpose applications.
- To develop procedures for web, social media and applications.

#### **Database Developer**

QVC Softwares.

June 2016 to August 2016

- To develop database using SQL server and Visual C# in a team.
- To integrate the Layout from Visual C# to Database.

#### Education

### **Bachelor of Science in Software Engineering**

Sir Syed University of Engineering & Technology - Karachi

#### Intermediate in Pre-Engineering

Govt. College For Men - Karachi 2013

#### **Matriculation**

Emmi's Institute For Learning - Karachi 2011

#### Skills

- Unity Game Engine (PC, Android, iOS, WebGL, AR, VR, Multiplayer)
- IBM Watson for Unity
- Blender
- Substance Painter
- · Pixologic's Zbrush
- Adobe Suite (Photoshop, Illustrator, Premiere, After Effects)
- JSON
- Node.js, Unity .jslib, WebRTC, Web sockets, Rest API

#### Links

https://usamaqh.github.io/usamaqureshi/

https://www.linkedin.com/in/usamagh/

#### Awards

# First position at All Karachi Project Competition at Sir Syed University 2018

Our VR project "Devil's Whisper" was awarded First position at All Karachi Project Competition at Sir Syed University 2018.

# Regional Finals Winner at Microsoft's Imagine Cup 2018, Islamabad.

2018

Our VR project "Devil's Whisper" won the Regional Finals at Microsoft's Imagine Cup 2018, Islamabad. We were sponsored by Microsoft to attend and compete in the Microsoft's Imagine Cup 2018, Islamabad.

# First position at HUPEC FYP competition at Hamdard University 2017

We got First position for our VR project "Devil's Whisper" at HUPEC FYP competition at Hamdard University 2017 for best and innovative FYP project of the competition.

# First position at ZUFEST ZURIC Project Competition, Ziauddin University 2017

We held First position at ZUFEST ZURIC Project Competition, Ziauddin University 2017 for our VR project Devil's Whisper.

# **Project Showcase, HEC at NED University 2017**

2017

We were invited to showcase our project "Devil's Whisper" by HEC at NED University 2017.

# Called for Motivational speech by Sir Syed University

2018

We were invited in 2018 FYP orientation at Sir Syed University, to motivate and counsel the new batch regarding new technologies emerging and new ideas for projects.

# **Seminar On Virtual & Augmented Reality - Invited Speaker**

2019

Invited to conduct a seminar and speak on the latest trends in the market for Augmented and Virtual reality technologies, to provide the university student's a source of motivation & skillful knowledge.

#### Certifications and Licenses

### Diploma In Graphics Suite, Arena Multimedia.

2012 to 2013

Distinction in graphics suite diploma at Arena Multimedia. Covered range of graphic designing skills, from 2D designing to video editing.